{
  "article_id": "2025-01-04_30aa4a7adc76b9d8ba8ba3fd9f307234",
  "source_info": {
    "source_name": "APP",
    "source_link": "https://www.app.com.pk/national/india-issues-visas-to-only-100-pakistani-pilgrims-for-khwaja-moinuddin-chishtis-urs/",
    "retrieved_at": "2025-08-27T11:20:44.824Z"
  },
  "metadata": {
    "title": "India issues visas to only 100 Pakistani pilgrims for Khwaja Moinuddin Chishti’s Urs",
    "author": null,
    "date_published": "2025-01-04T18:03:00.000Z",
    "image_url": null,
    "categories": [],
    "word_count": 117,
    "reading_time_minutes": 1
  },
  "content": {
    "article_body": "ISLAMABAD, Jan 04 (APP): The Indian authorities have issued visas to only 100 Pakistani pilgrims for the annual Urs of Hazrat Khwaja Moinuddin Chishti in Ajmer Sharif, India, significantly below the allotted quota of 500. According to the spokesperson for the Ministry of Religious Affairs and Interfaith Harmony, Muhammad Umar Butt on Saturday, this year, India has restricted the number of visas issued, denying travel to 400 potential pilgrims. Despite the restrictions, he said 100 Pakistani pilgrims are set to leave for Ajmer Sharif on Sunday via the Wagah border. These pilgrims will participate in various religious ceremonies at the shrine of the revered Sufi saint, Hazrat Khwaja Moinuddin Chishti, widely known as Gharib Nawaz, he added.",
    "summary": "India issued visas to only 100 Pakistani pilgrims for the annual Urs of Hazrat Khwaja Moinuddin Chishti in Ajmer Sharif, significantly below the allotted quota of 500. The spokesperson for the Ministry of Religious Affairs and Interfaith Harmony, Muhammad Umar Butt, stated that 400 potential pilgrims were denied travel. Despite the restrictions, 100 pilgrims are scheduled to travel via the Wagah border.",
    "keywords": [
      "India",
      "visas",
      "pilgrims",
      "Ajmer Sharif",
      "Khwaja Moinuddin Chishti",
      "Wagah border"
    ]
  },
  "entities": [
    {
      "text": "India",
      "label": "LOCATION",
      "wikidata_id": "Q668"
    },
    {
      "text": "Pakistani",
      "label": "PERSON",
      "wikidata_id": "Q1009"
    },
    {
      "text": "Khwaja Moinuddin Chishti",
      "label": "PERSON",
      "wikidata_id": "Q3196933"
    },
    {
      "text": "Ajmer Sharif",
      "label": "LOCATION",
      "wikidata_id": "Q470077"
    },
    {
      "text": "Muhammad Umar Butt",
      "label": "PERSON",
      "wikidata_id": "null"
    },
    {
      "text": "Ministry of Religious Affairs and Interfaith Harmony",
      "label": "ORGANIZATION",
      "wikidata_id": "null"
    },
    {
      "text": "Wagah border",
      "label": "LOCATION",
      "wikidata_id": "Q7961239"
    },
    {
      "text": "Hazrat Khwaja Moinuddin Chishti",
      "label": "PERSON",
      "wikidata_id": "Q3196933"
    },
    {
      "text": "Gharib Nawaz",
      "label": "PERSON",
      "wikidata_id": "Q5524097"
    }
  ]
}