{
  "article_id": "2025-01-04_2e35b844061a39ef9ae9ab9a3fe18a9c",
  "source_info": {
    "source_name": "APP",
    "source_link": "https://www.app.com.pk/national/death-anniversary-of-poet-lyricist-tufail-hoshiarpuri-observed/",
    "retrieved_at": "2025-08-27T11:20:31.684Z"
  },
  "metadata": {
    "title": "Death anniversary of poet, lyricist Tufail Hoshiarpuri observed",
    "author": null,
    "date_published": "2025-01-04T07:28:00.000Z",
    "image_url": null,
    "categories": [],
    "word_count": 119,
    "reading_time_minutes": 1
  },
  "content": {
    "article_body": "ISLAMABAD, Jan 4 (APP):The 32nd death anniversary of renowned poet and lyricist Tufail Hoshiarpuri was observed on Saturday. Muhammad Tufail was born on July 14, 1914, near Gauran Gate, Sheesh Mahal Bazar, in Hoshiarpur, Punjab, British India. His name later was changed to Tufail Hoshiarpuri as his professional name. After the partition in 1947, he migrated to Lahore, Pakistan, and started his career as a journalist there. He later joined Radio Pakistan, Lahore, in 1952. His famous patriotic song was aAi Mard e Mujahid Jaag Zaraa. He was awarded the Pride of Performance Award by the President of Pakistan in 1994. Tufail Hoshiarpuri died onA January 4, 1993, and was buried in the Model Town, Lahore graveyard in Pakistan.",
    "summary": "The 32nd death anniversary of poet and lyricist Tufail Hoshiarpuri was observed. He was born in British India and later migrated to Pakistan after the partition. He was known for his patriotic song and received the Pride of Performance Award.",
    "keywords": [
      "Tufail Hoshiarpuri",
      "death anniversary",
      "poet",
      "lyricist",
      "Lahore",
      "Pakistan",
      "patriotic song"
    ]
  },
  "entities": [
    {
      "text": "Tufail Hoshiarpuri",
      "label": "PERSON",
      "wikidata_id": "null"
    },
    {
      "text": "Muhammad Tufail",
      "label": "PERSON",
      "wikidata_id": "null"
    },
    {
      "text": "Hoshiarpur",
      "label": "LOCATION",
      "wikidata_id": "Q199736"
    },
    {
      "text": "Punjab",
      "label": "LOCATION",
      "wikidata_id": "Q180727"
    },
    {
      "text": "British India",
      "label": "LOCATION",
      "wikidata_id": "Q79864"
    },
    {
      "text": "Lahore",
      "label": "LOCATION",
      "wikidata_id": "Q5597"
    },
    {
      "text": "Pakistan",
      "label": "LOCATION",
      "wikidata_id": "Q843"
    },
    {
      "text": "Radio Pakistan",
      "label": "ORGANIZATION",
      "wikidata_id": "Q7280877"
    },
    {
      "text": "President of Pakistan",
      "label": "PERSON",
      "wikidata_id": "null"
    },
    {
      "text": "Model Town, Lahore",
      "label": "LOCATION",
      "wikidata_id": "null"
    }
  ]
}