{
  "article_id": "2025-01-11_c750d6e9f20e10562da8b8b165f0f735",
  "source_info": {
    "source_name": "APP",
    "source_link": "https://www.app.com.pk/national/cultural-evening-at-pnca-enchants-international-delegates-with-vibrant-performances/",
    "retrieved_at": "2025-08-27T11:32:57.457Z"
  },
  "metadata": {
    "title": "Cultural Evening at PNCA enchants int’l delegates with vibrant performances",
    "author": null,
    "date_published": "2025-01-11T17:14:00.000Z",
    "image_url": null,
    "categories": [],
    "word_count": 252,
    "reading_time_minutes": 2
  },
  "content": {
    "article_body": "ISLAMABAD, Jan 11 (APP): A cultural soiree at the Pakistan National Council of Arts (PNCA) enthralled international delegates with a spectacular display of talent celebrating the countryas rich heritage, music, art and traditions. Organized by the Ministry of Federal Education and Professional Training in collaboration with the National Heritage and Cultural Division, the Cultural Evening was held in honour of the delegates attending the International Conference on Girlsa Education, which was attended by academics as well as representatives from UNESCO, UNICEF, and the World Bank. Secretary of the Ministry of Information and Broadcasting, Ms. Ambreen Jan, along with senior officials of the National Heritage and Culture Division, welcomed the delegations. The delegates also explored PNCAas galleries and admired the artworks of Pakistani artists, following a briefing by Mariyam Ahmed. The eveningas performances were a testament to the rich cultural heritage of Pakistan. Salman Adilas flute melodies captivated the guests, while Dr. Masuma Anwar, a nominee for the prestigious Pride of Performance award, enchanted the crowd with her renditions of Sufi and pop music. Also mesmerizing the audience was the Sindhi Jhumar dance, followed by the soulful sounds of Ali Raza Khan playing the Kashmiri Santoor. Hamza Khan, a talented Rubab player, won the hearts of the delegates with lilting tunes, while the evening culminated with a medley of dance performances from across Pakistan, which equally captivated all in attendance. The Cultural Evening showcased Pakistanas artistic diversity in an effective manner that is bound to leave a lasting impression on the visiting delegates.",
    "summary": "A cultural soiree at the Pakistan National Council of Arts (PNCA) enthralled international delegates with a spectacular display of talent celebrating Pakistan's rich heritage, music, art and traditions. The event was organized by the Ministry of Federal Education and Professional Training in collaboration with the National Heritage and Cultural Division.",
    "keywords": [
      "Pakistan National Council of Arts (PNCA)",
      "Cultural Evening",
      "UNESCO",
      "UNICEF",
      "World Bank",
      "Ambreen Jan",
      "Salman Adil"
    ]
  },
  "entities": [
    {
      "type": "PERSON",
      "name": "Ambreen Jan",
      "wiki_data_id": null,
      "sentiment": "Positive"
    },
    {
      "type": "PERSON",
      "name": "Salman Adil",
      "wiki_data_id": null,
      "sentiment": "Neutral"
    },
    {
      "type": "PERSON",
      "name": "Mariyam Ahmed",
      "wiki_data_id": null,
      "sentiment": "Positive"
    },
    {
      "type": "ORGANIZATION",
      "name": "UNESCO",
      "wiki_data_id": "Q173371",
      "sentiment": "Neutral"
    },
    {
      "type": "ORGANIZATION",
      "name": "UNICEF",
      "wiki_data_id": "Q181523",
      "sentiment": "Neutral"
    },
    {
      "type": "ORGANIZATION",
      "name": "World Bank",
      "wiki_data_id": "Q183",
      "sentiment": "Neutral"
    },
    {
      "type": "LOCATION",
      "name": "Pakistan National Council of Arts (PNCA)",
      "wiki_data_id": null,
      "sentiment": "Positive"
    },
    {
      "type": "PERSON",
      "name": "Dr. Masuma Anwar",
      "wiki_data_id": null,
      "sentiment": "Neutral"
    },
    {
      "type": "PERSON",
      "name": "Ali Raza Khan",
      "wiki_data_id": null,
      "sentiment": "Positive"
    },
    {
      "type": "LOCATION",
      "name": "Pakistan",
      "wiki_data_id": null,
      "sentiment": "Neutral"
    },
    {
      "type": "PERSON",
      "name": "Hamza Khan",
      "wiki_data_id": null,
      "sentiment": "Positive"
    }
  ]
}