{
  "article_id": "2025-01-07_83e4bfda35a3e39968ab86394b05ee31",
  "source_info": {
    "source_name": "APP",
    "source_link": "https://www.app.com.pk/national/regional-countries-diplomats-visit-ndma-to-explore-neoc-capabilities-foster-cooperation-on-disaster-management/",
    "retrieved_at": "2025-08-27T11:26:57.900Z"
  },
  "metadata": {
    "title": "Regional countries diplomats visit NDMA to explore NEOC capabilities, foster cooperation on disaster management",
    "author": null,
    "date_published": "2025-01-07T13:08:00.000Z",
    "image_url": null,
    "categories": [],
    "word_count": 271,
    "reading_time_minutes": 2
  },
  "content": {
    "article_body": "ISLAMABAD, Jan 07 (APP):Representatives and members from the Shanghai Cooperation Organization (SCO), Economic Cooperation Organization (ECO), and South Asian Association for Regional Cooperation (SAARC) Tuesday visited the National Disaster Management Authority (NDMA) to review the capabilities of the National Emergency Operations Centre (NEOC). The delegation was briefed on the state-of-the-art technological infrastructure and operational frameworks designed to tackle climate-induced anomalies and disasters in Pakistan and the region. During the briefing, rising temperatures, coastline crises, and their impacts on regional stability were highlighted. Chairman NDMA Lt. Gen Inam Haider Malik HM(I) briefed the delegation about the capacities of NEOC. The delegated were briefed about escalating impacts of rising temperatures on the region, stressing the importance of collaborative action to address shared vulnerabilities. Call for action for utilization of NEOCas advanced systems for real-time monitoring, disaster preparedness, and response in the region. They were also briefed about potential of a regional framework for disaster risk reduction (DRR), emphasizing joint efforts for capacity building and knowledge sharing to strengthen disaster preparedness and response. Secretary General of ECO Secretariat, Ambassador Dr. Asad Majeed Khan, commended NDMAas efforts in disaster preparedness and urged regional member states to prioritize disaster risk reduction frameworks. He noted that ECO member countries face a collective loss of $70 million due to climate-related disasters annually, making regional cooperation an urgent necessity. Ambassador of Iran Dr. Reza Amiri, Ambassador Uzbekistan, Oybek Usmanov, Ambassador of Nepal, Rita Dhital, AmbassadorA of Azerbaijan, Khazar Farhadov,A Bangladesh High commissioner to Pakistan Iqbal Hussain Khan, DHM Islamail MufeedA and representativeA from Kazakhstan, Kyrgyzstan, Sri Lanka, MaldivesA and official of Ministry of foreign affairs attended the session .",
    "summary": "Representatives from regional countries visited the National Disaster Management Authority (NDMA) to review the capabilities of the National Emergency Operations Centre (NEOC). The delegation was briefed on the state-of-the-art technological infrastructure and operational frameworks designed to tackle climate-induced anomalies and disasters in Pakistan and the region. They were also briefed about potential collaborations for disaster risk reduction and response.",
    "keywords": [
      "Disaster Management",
      "Regional Cooperation",
      "Climate Change",
      "Pakistan",
      "NEOC",
      "NDMA",
      "SAARC",
      "ECO"
    ]
  },
  "entities": [
    {
      "type": "ORGANIZATION",
      "name": "National Disaster Management Authority (NDMA)",
      "wikiDataId": null
    },
    {
      "type": "LOCATION",
      "name": "Pakistan",
      "wikiDataId": null
    },
    {
      "type": "ORGANIZATION",
      "name": "Shanghai Cooperation Organization (SCO)",
      "wikiDataId": null
    },
    {
      "type": "ORGANIZATION",
      "name": "Economic Cooperation Organization (ECO)",
      "wikiDataId": "Q1192443"
    },
    {
      "type": "LOCATION",
      "name": "South Asia",
      "wikiDataId": null
    },
    {
      "type": "ORGANIZATION",
      "name": "SAARC (South Asian Association for Regional Cooperation)",
      "wikiDataId": null
    },
    {
      "type": "PERSON",
      "name": "Lt. Gen Inam Haider Malik HM(I)",
      "wikiDataId": null
    },
    {
      "type": "ORGANIZATION",
      "name": "National Emergency Operations Centre (NEOC)",
      "wikiDataId": null
    },
    {
      "type": "PERSON",
      "name": "Dr. Asad Majeed Khan",
      "wikiDataId": null
    },
    {
      "type": "LOCATION",
      "name": "Iran",
      "wikiDataId": null
    },
    {
      "type": "ORGANIZATION",
      "name": "Uzbekistan",
      "wikiDataId": "Q123"
    },
    {
      "type": "PERSON",
      "name": "Rita Dhital",
      "wikiDataId": null
    },
    {
      "type": "LOCATION",
      "name": "Nepal",
      "wikiDataId": null
    },
    {
      "type": "ORGANIZATION",
      "name": "Azerbaijan",
      "wikiDataId": null
    },
    {
      "type": "PERSON",
      "name": "Khazar Farhadov",
      "wikiDataId": null
    },
    {
      "type": "LOCATION",
      "name": "Bangladesh",
      "wikiDataId": null
    },
    {
      "type": "PERSON",
      "name": "Iqbal Hussain Khan",
      "wikiDataId": null
    },
    {
      "type": "LOCATION",
      "name": "Kazakhstan",
      "wikiDataId": null
    },
    {
      "type": "ORGANIZATION",
      "name": "Kyrgyzstan",
      "wikiDataId": null
    },
    {
      "type": "PERSON",
      "name": "Oybek Usmanov",
      "wikiDataId": null
    },
    {
      "type": "LOCATION",
      "name": "Sri Lanka",
      "wikiDataId": null
    },
    {
      "type": "ORGANIZATION",
      "name": "Maldives",
      "wikiDataId": null
    },
    {
      "type": "PERSON",
      "name": "Islamail MufeedA",
      "wikiDataId": null
    }
  ]
}