{
  "article_id": "2025-01-05_8f256ca06d4e1bcca8385e3b398ef5c5",
  "source_info": {
    "source_name": "APP",
    "source_link": "https://www.app.com.pk/national/zulfiqar-ali-bhutto-remembered-on-his-97th-birth-anniversary/",
    "retrieved_at": "2025-08-27T11:23:20.004Z"
  },
  "metadata": {
    "title": "Zulfiqar Ali Bhutto remembered on his 97th birth anniversary",
    "author": null,
    "date_published": "2025-01-05T07:20:00.000Z",
    "image_url": null,
    "categories": [],
    "word_count": 231,
    "reading_time_minutes": 2
  },
  "content": {
    "article_body": "ISLAMABAD, Jan 5 (APP): The 97th birth anniversary of Pakistanas former prime minister and Pakistan Peopleas Party (PPP) founder, Zulfikar Ali Bhutto, is being commemorated on Sunday. Bhutto was born on this day in 1928 in Larkana. He completed his early education at Bombayas Cathedral High School. He joined the University of Southern California in 1947 and later the University of California at Berkeley in June 1949. After completing his degree with honors in Political Science at Berkeley in June 1950, he was admitted to Oxford. Bhutto was then called to the Bar at Lincolnas Inn in 1953. On his return to Pakistan, Bhutto started practicing law at Dingomalas. In 1958, he joined President Iskander Mirzaas Cabinet as commerce minister. He was the youngest minister in Ayub Khanas cabinet. In 1963, he took over the post of Foreign Minister from Muhammad Ali Bogra. His first major achievement was concluding the Sino-Pakistan boundary agreement on March 2a 1963. In mid-1964, Bhutto helped convince Ayub of the wisdom of establishing closer economic and diplomatic links with Turkey and Iran. He laid the foundation of the Pakistan Peopleas Party on November 30, 1967. Bhutto also made the countryas defense impregnable by starting a nuclear program. He served as president of Pakistan from 1971 to 1973 and prime minister of Pakistan from 1973 to 1977. One of Bhuttoas greatest achievements was the Constitution of 1973.",
    "summary": "Zulfiqar Ali Bhutto's 97th birth anniversary was commemorated. He was a former prime minister and founder of the Pakistan People's Party. Bhutto's career included roles as a minister, foreign minister, and president, with significant achievements such as the 1973 Constitution.",
    "keywords": [
      "Zulfikar Ali Bhutto",
      "Pakistan",
      "Pakistan People's Party",
      "birth anniversary",
      "prime minister",
      "Constitution of 1973",
      "Foreign Minister"
    ]
  },
  "entities": [
    {
      "text": "Zulfikar Ali Bhutto",
      "label": "PERSON",
      "wikidata_id": "Q312953"
    },
    {
      "text": "Pakistan",
      "label": "LOCATION",
      "wikidata_id": "Q843"
    },
    {
      "text": "Pakistan Peopleas Party",
      "label": "ORGANIZATION",
      "wikidata_id": "Q1197945"
    },
    {
      "text": "Bombayas Cathedral High School",
      "label": "ORGANIZATION",
      "wikidata_id": "null"
    },
    {
      "text": "University of Southern California",
      "label": "ORGANIZATION",
      "wikidata_id": "Q18585"
    },
    {
      "text": "University of California at Berkeley",
      "label": "ORGANIZATION",
      "wikidata_id": "Q13398"
    },
    {
      "text": "Oxford",
      "label": "ORGANIZATION",
      "wikidata_id": "Q33997"
    },
    {
      "text": "Lincolnas Inn",
      "label": "ORGANIZATION",
      "wikidata_id": "Q1860654"
    },
    {
      "text": "President Iskander Mirzaas",
      "label": "PERSON",
      "wikidata_id": "Q313532"
    },
    {
      "text": "Ayub Khanas",
      "label": "PERSON",
      "wikidata_id": "Q154462"
    },
    {
      "text": "Muhammad Ali Bogra",
      "label": "PERSON",
      "wikidata_id": "Q734065"
    },
    {
      "text": "Turkey",
      "label": "LOCATION",
      "wikidata_id": "Q43"
    },
    {
      "text": "Iran",
      "label": "LOCATION",
      "wikidata_id": "Q794"
    }
  ]
}