{
  "article_id": "2025-01-05_f8db778d4c3a155a6120989fdcce983f",
  "source_info": {
    "source_name": "APP",
    "source_link": "https://www.app.com.pk/national/4th-intl-hydropower-conference-to-be-held-on-jan-9/",
    "retrieved_at": "2025-08-27T11:22:45.323Z"
  },
  "metadata": {
    "title": "4th Int’l Hydropower conference to be held on Jan 9",
    "author": null,
    "date_published": "2025-01-05T10:50:00.000Z",
    "image_url": null,
    "categories": [],
    "word_count": 324,
    "reading_time_minutes": 2
  },
  "content": {
    "article_body": "ISLAMABAD, Jan 05 (APP):4th International Hydropower Conference 2025, hosted by Energy Update in Collaboration with Private Power Infrastructure Board (PPIB) & International Hydropower Association, is set to be held here on January 9. This landmark event will bring together industry leaders, policymakers, and global experts to discuss hydropoweras transformative role in shaping a sustainable energy future for Pakistan. The event will feature an inaugural session with key addresses by M. Naeem Qureshi, Managing Editor of Energy Update; Shah Jahan Mirza, Managing Director, Private Power Infrastructure Board (PPIB); Eddie Rich, CEO of the International Hydropower Association (joining online); Hafiz Isahaq, CEO, TNB Remaco Malaysia; and Dr. Musadik Malik, Federal Minister for Water Resources, who is expected to join as the Chief Guest, will also deliver an address. Interactive sessions will include presentations by Senator Mushahid Hussain Sayed, Azam Joya (GM C&M Water), Asim Javed (Hydropower Expert), Dr. Irfan Yousaf (CEO, MKAI Climate Consulting), Dr. Hassan Daud Butt (Senior Advisor, CEEC), and Dr. Jehanzeb Nasir (Energy Systems Engineer, NUST), who will cover topics ranging from financing challenges to emerging technologies and strategic hydropower roles. Panel discussions will delve into hydropoweras critical role in Pakistanas energy sector, featuring contributions from Dr. Munawar Iqbal Kamboh (DG Hydel, PPIB), Arfan Miana (CEO, Neelum Jhelum Hydropower), Shukree (Outgoing CEO, TNB Remaco Malaysia), Dr. Parvaiz Naim (External Advisor, KFW Development Bank), and M. Ayub Khan (CEO, KPKTDC). The conference will culminate with a session on parliamentary leadership in energy transition, chaired by Prof. Ahsan Iqbal, Federal Minister for Planning, Development, and Special Initiatives, who is also expected to join as chief guest. The session will feature prominent voices, including Dr. Nafisa Shah (MNA), Dr. Shazrey Munsab Ali Khan (MNA & Parliamentary Secretary, MoFA), Dr. Amjad Ali Khan (MNA & Member, Energy Nexus Economy Forum), and Senator Saadia Abbasi. This event provides an unparalleled platform to discuss hydropoweras transformative potential, untapped opportunities, and the collaborative efforts needed to secure Pakistanas energy future.",
    "summary": "The 4th International Hydropower Conference 2025 will be held in Islamabad on January 9th. The conference, hosted by Energy Update in collaboration with several organizations, will bring together industry leaders and experts to discuss the role of hydropower in Pakistan's sustainable energy future. Key figures, including government officials and industry leaders, will deliver addresses and participate in interactive sessions and panel discussions.",
    "keywords": [
      "hydropower",
      "conference",
      "Pakistan",
      "energy",
      "Islamabad",
      "sustainability",
      "renewable energy"
    ]
  },
  "entities": [
    {
      "text": "Islamabad",
      "label": "LOCATION",
      "wikidata_id": "Q1166"
    },
    {
      "text": "Energy Update",
      "label": "ORGANIZATION",
      "wikidata_id": "null"
    },
    {
      "text": "Private Power Infrastructure Board (PPIB)",
      "label": "ORGANIZATION",
      "wikidata_id": "null"
    },
    {
      "text": "International Hydropower Association",
      "label": "ORGANIZATION",
      "wikidata_id": "Q1696019"
    },
    {
      "text": "M. Naeem Qureshi",
      "label": "PERSON",
      "wikidata_id": "null"
    },
    {
      "text": "Shah Jahan Mirza",
      "label": "PERSON",
      "wikidata_id": "null"
    },
    {
      "text": "Eddie Rich",
      "label": "PERSON",
      "wikidata_id": "null"
    },
    {
      "text": "Hafiz Isahaq",
      "label": "PERSON",
      "wikidata_id": "null"
    },
    {
      "text": "Dr. Musadik Malik",
      "label": "PERSON",
      "wikidata_id": "null"
    },
    {
      "text": "Senator Mushahid Hussain Sayed",
      "label": "PERSON",
      "wikidata_id": "null"
    },
    {
      "text": "Azam Joya",
      "label": "PERSON",
      "wikidata_id": "null"
    },
    {
      "text": "Asim Javed",
      "label": "PERSON",
      "wikidata_id": "null"
    },
    {
      "text": "Dr. Irfan Yousaf",
      "label": "PERSON",
      "wikidata_id": "null"
    },
    {
      "text": "Dr. Hassan Daud Butt",
      "label": "PERSON",
      "wikidata_id": "null"
    },
    {
      "text": "Dr. Jehanzeb Nasir",
      "label": "PERSON",
      "wikidata_id": "null"
    },
    {
      "text": "Dr. Munawar Iqbal Kamboh",
      "label": "PERSON",
      "wikidata_id": "null"
    },
    {
      "text": "Arfan Miana",
      "label": "PERSON",
      "wikidata_id": "null"
    },
    {
      "text": "Shukree",
      "label": "PERSON",
      "wikidata_id": "null"
    },
    {
      "text": "Dr. Parvaiz Naim",
      "label": "PERSON",
      "wikidata_id": "null"
    },
    {
      "text": "M. Ayub Khan",
      "label": "PERSON",
      "wikidata_id": "null"
    },
    {
      "text": "Prof. Ahsan Iqbal",
      "label": "PERSON",
      "wikidata_id": "null"
    },
    {
      "text": "Dr. Nafisa Shah",
      "label": "PERSON",
      "wikidata_id": "null"
    },
    {
      "text": "Dr. Shazrey Munsab Ali Khan",
      "label": "PERSON",
      "wikidata_id": "null"
    },
    {
      "text": "Dr. Amjad Ali Khan",
      "label": "PERSON",
      "wikidata_id": "null"
    },
    {
      "text": "Senator Saadia Abbasi",
      "label": "PERSON",
      "wikidata_id": "null"
    },
    {
      "text": "TNB Remaco Malaysia",
      "label": "ORGANIZATION",
      "wikidata_id": "null"
    },
    {
      "text": "KFW Development Bank",
      "label": "ORGANIZATION",
      "wikidata_id": "Q151838"
    },
    {
      "text": "KPKTDC",
      "label": "ORGANIZATION",
      "wikidata_id": "null"
    },
    {
      "text": "NUST",
      "label": "ORGANIZATION",
      "wikidata_id": "Q7071658"
    },
    {
      "text": "CEEC",
      "label": "ORGANIZATION",
      "wikidata_id": "null"
    },
    {
      "text": "MKAI Climate Consulting",
      "label": "ORGANIZATION",
      "wikidata_id": "null"
    },
    {
      "text": "MoFA",
      "label": "ORGANIZATION",
      "wikidata_id": "Q1056860"
    }
  ]
}