{
  "article_id": "2025-01-02_52533a807c8bedeae9aaf947158878f9",
  "source_info": {
    "source_name": "APP",
    "source_link": "https://www.app.com.pk/national/talks-held-in-conducive-environment-pti-to-present-cod-in-next-meeting-ayaz-sadiq/",
    "retrieved_at": "2025-08-27T11:16:46.056Z"
  },
  "metadata": {
    "title": "Talks held in conducive environment; PTI to present CoD in next meeting: Ayaz Sadiq",
    "author": null,
    "date_published": "2025-01-02T17:59:00.000Z",
    "image_url": null,
    "categories": [],
    "word_count": 466,
    "reading_time_minutes": 3
  },
  "content": {
    "article_body": "ISLAMABAD, Jan 02 (APP):National Assembly Speaker Ayaz Sadiq on Thursday expressed satisfaction over the talks held between the government and opposition committees, describing them as being conducted in a amore conducive environment.a The Pakistan Tehreek-e-Insaf (PTI) would present its aCharter of Demandsa in the next meeting, he said, while talking to journalists after the conclusion of the second round of talks. He said, aIn the last meeting, we decided that PTI would present its charter of demands. However, the opposition requested another meeting with [PTI founder] to finalize their list of demands. The next meeting will hopefully take place next week,a. Welcoming the cordial environment of the discussions, he said that Khyber Pakhtunkhwa Chief Minister Ali Amin Gandapur also tabled aexcellent proposals and spoke with an open heart.a He said, that the most positive outcome was the consensus among all participants to engage in dialogue for Pakistanas betterment, covering issues such as the economy, terrorism, and other critical matters. Senator Irfan Siddiqui, read out a joint statement, highlighting that the PTI Committee, led by Umar Ayub Khan and comprising other members, presented a detailed perspective. The committee demanded the release of PTIas founding chairman Imran Khan, along with other party leaders and workers. They also called for the government to refrain from creating obstacles for PTI workers seeking bail. They proposed the formation of a judicial commission to thoroughly investigate and disclose the facts regarding the incidents of May 9 and November 26. They said that Imran Khan had authorized the initiation of negotiations, and the committee required clear instructions to proceed methodically. Following consultations with Imran Khan, the final charter of demands would be presented in the next meeting. On behalf of the governmentas parliamentary committee, Deputy Prime Minister and Foreign Minister Ishaq Dar said that, based on the decisions of the previous meeting, it was expected that PTI would present its demands in writing during Thursdayas session. However, he expressed no objections to PTIas committee seeking guidance from Imran Khan before finalizing their demands. He added that both committees could then proceed amicably. It was agreed that once PTIas committee completes consultations, a date for the third meeting would be set for next week. The governmentas side included Deputy Prime Minister and Foreign Minister Ishaq Dar, PML-N Senator Irfan Siddiqui, PPP MNAs Raja Pervaiz Ashraf and Naveed Qamar, Adviser to the Prime Minister on Political and Public Affairs Rana Sanaullah, MQM-P lawmaker Farooq Sattar, Balochistan Awami Party lawmaker Khalid Magsi, Pakistan Muslim League Zia Ejaz-ul-Haq and Federal Minister for privatization Abdul Aleem Khan. From the oppositionas side, the participants included Umar Ayub, Khyber Pakhtunkhwa Chief Minister Ali Amin Gandapur, PTI MNA Asad Qaiser, Sunni Ittehad Council chief Hamid Raza, Majlis Wahdat-i-Muslimeen chief Senator Raja Nasir Abbas Jafri, and PTI Secretary General Salman Akram Raja.",
    "summary": "Talks between the government and the Pakistan Tehreek-e-Insaf (PTI) were held in a conducive environment, with the PTI set to present its Charter of Demands in the next meeting. The discussions focused on various issues, including the economy and terrorism, with both sides agreeing to engage in dialogue for Pakistan's betterment. The PTI committee, led by Umar Ayub Khan, demanded the release of Imran Khan and other party members, along with a judicial commission to investigate past incidents.",
    "keywords": [
      "PTI",
      "dialogue",
      "Imran Khan",
      "Charter of Demands",
      "government"
    ]
  },
  "entities": [
    {
      "text": "Ayaz Sadiq",
      "label": "PERSON",
      "wikidata_id": "null"
    },
    {
      "text": "PTI",
      "label": "ORGANIZATION",
      "wikidata_id": "Q7122789"
    },
    {
      "text": "Pakistan Tehreek-e-Insaf",
      "label": "ORGANIZATION",
      "wikidata_id": "Q7122789"
    },
    {
      "text": "Ali Amin Gandapur",
      "label": "PERSON",
      "wikidata_id": "null"
    },
    {
      "text": "Imran Khan",
      "label": "PERSON",
      "wikidata_id": "Q57989"
    },
    {
      "text": "Umar Ayub Khan",
      "label": "PERSON",
      "wikidata_id": "null"
    },
    {
      "text": "Ishaq Dar",
      "label": "PERSON",
      "wikidata_id": "Q6078021"
    },
    {
      "text": "Irfan Siddiqui",
      "label": "PERSON",
      "wikidata_id": "null"
    },
    {
      "text": "Raja Pervaiz Ashraf",
      "label": "PERSON",
      "wikidata_id": "Q7285686"
    },
    {
      "text": "Naveed Qamar",
      "label": "PERSON",
      "wikidata_id": "null"
    },
    {
      "text": "Rana Sanaullah",
      "label": "PERSON",
      "wikidata_id": "Q7290098"
    },
    {
      "text": "Farooq Sattar",
      "label": "PERSON",
      "wikidata_id": "Q5435954"
    },
    {
      "text": "Khalid Magsi",
      "label": "PERSON",
      "wikidata_id": "null"
    },
    {
      "text": "Ejaz-ul-Haq",
      "label": "PERSON",
      "wikidata_id": "null"
    },
    {
      "text": "Abdul Aleem Khan",
      "label": "PERSON",
      "wikidata_id": "null"
    },
    {
      "text": "Asad Qaiser",
      "label": "PERSON",
      "wikidata_id": "Q4803730"
    },
    {
      "text": "Hamid Raza",
      "label": "PERSON",
      "wikidata_id": "null"
    },
    {
      "text": "Raja Nasir Abbas Jafri",
      "label": "PERSON",
      "wikidata_id": "null"
    },
    {
      "text": "Salman Akram Raja",
      "label": "PERSON",
      "wikidata_id": "null"
    },
    {
      "text": "Khyber Pakhtunkhwa",
      "label": "LOCATION",
      "wikidata_id": "Q12053"
    },
    {
      "text": "PML-N",
      "label": "ORGANIZATION",
      "wikidata_id": "Q270729"
    },
    {
      "text": "PPP",
      "label": "ORGANIZATION",
      "wikidata_id": "Q119429"
    },
    {
      "text": "MQM-P",
      "label": "ORGANIZATION",
      "wikidata_id": "Q671131"
    },
    {
      "text": "Balochistan Awami Party",
      "label": "ORGANIZATION",
      "wikidata_id": "null"
    },
    {
      "text": "Pakistan Muslim League Zia",
      "label": "ORGANIZATION",
      "wikidata_id": "null"
    },
    {
      "text": "Sunni Ittehad Council",
      "label": "ORGANIZATION",
      "wikidata_id": "null"
    },
    {
      "text": "Majlis Wahdat-i-Muslimeen",
      "label": "ORGANIZATION",
      "wikidata_id": "Q6736419"
    }
  ]
}