{
  "article_id": "2025-01-02_b9dc51710e718b917cbd3b9ba81e0cb5",
  "source_info": {
    "source_name": "APP",
    "source_link": "https://www.app.com.pk/national/strong-lg-vital-for-community-development-danial-chaudhry/",
    "retrieved_at": "2025-08-27T11:16:47.880Z"
  },
  "metadata": {
    "title": "Strong LG vital for community development: Danial Chaudhry",
    "author": null,
    "date_published": "2025-01-02T17:15:00.000Z",
    "image_url": null,
    "categories": [],
    "word_count": 194,
    "reading_time_minutes": 1
  },
  "content": {
    "article_body": "ISLAMABAD, Jan 02 (APP):Barrister Danial Chaudhry, the Parliamentary Secretary for Information and Broadcasting, stressed the importance of a strong local government system on Thursday for addressing public issues and fostering local development. Speaking at the Local Government Convention in Rawalpindi, Danial Chaudhry emphasized that the effectiveness of local government institutions is key to the communityas welfare. He further stated that a robust local government system is vital for resolving public issues and promoting local development. He also highlighted the aUraan Pakistan Economic Transformation Plan,a calling it a revolutionary initiative aimed at boosting the countryas economy. The participants of the convention reaffirmed their commitment to advancing development initiatives in the region, with a strong focus on public cooperation to drive progress. MNA Hanif Abbasi, also present at the convention, underscored the significant role local government institutions play in public welfare. He urged all representatives to collaborate for the development of Rawalpindi, further echoing the need for collective efforts in community progress. The event was attended by several prominent figures from the PML-N Rawalpindi chapter, including, former MNA Haji Pervez Khan, former Mayor Sardar Naseem Khan, former MNA Shakeel Awan, MPA Rahat Quddusi and Raja Hanif.",
    "summary": "Barrister Danial Chaudhry emphasized the importance of a strong local government system for community development at the Local Government Convention in Rawalpindi. He highlighted the role of local government institutions in addressing public issues and promoting local development. The convention focused on advancing development initiatives with public cooperation.",
    "keywords": [
      "local government",
      "Rawalpindi",
      "community development",
      "public issues",
      "Danial Chaudhry",
      "convention",
      "PML-N"
    ]
  },
  "entities": [
    {
      "text": "Danial Chaudhry",
      "label": "PERSON",
      "wikidata_id": "null"
    },
    {
      "text": "Rawalpindi",
      "label": "LOCATION",
      "wikidata_id": "Q1166"
    },
    {
      "text": "Local Government Convention",
      "label": "ORGANIZATION",
      "wikidata_id": "null"
    },
    {
      "text": "Hanif Abbasi",
      "label": "PERSON",
      "wikidata_id": "null"
    },
    {
      "text": "PML-N",
      "label": "ORGANIZATION",
      "wikidata_id": "Q712953"
    },
    {
      "text": "Haji Pervez Khan",
      "label": "PERSON",
      "wikidata_id": "null"
    },
    {
      "text": "Sardar Naseem Khan",
      "label": "PERSON",
      "wikidata_id": "null"
    },
    {
      "text": "Shakeel Awan",
      "label": "PERSON",
      "wikidata_id": "null"
    },
    {
      "text": "Rahat Quddusi",
      "label": "PERSON",
      "wikidata_id": "null"
    },
    {
      "text": "Raja Hanif",
      "label": "PERSON",
      "wikidata_id": "null"
    },
    {
      "text": "Islamabad",
      "label": "LOCATION",
      "wikidata_id": "Q1036"
    }
  ]
}