{
  "article_id": "2025-01-02_29756036482432e6e6fd6c6498952834",
  "source_info": {
    "source_name": "APP",
    "source_link": "https://www.app.com.pk/national/shafqat-ali-khan-made-new-fo-spox-as-mumtaz-zahra-posted-in-paris/",
    "retrieved_at": "2025-08-27T11:15:53.381Z"
  },
  "metadata": {
    "title": "Shafqat Ali Khan made new FO spox as Mumtaz Zahra posted in Paris",
    "author": null,
    "date_published": "2025-01-02T09:56:00.000Z",
    "image_url": null,
    "categories": [],
    "word_count": 151,
    "reading_time_minutes": 1
  },
  "content": {
    "article_body": "ISLAMABAD, Jan 2 (APP): Career diplomat Shafqat Ali Khan has been appointed the new Foreign Office spokesperson, replacing Mumtaz Zahra Baloch. The announcement was made by Deputy Prime Minister and Foreign Minister Ishaq Dar at a press conference here on Thursday who hailed the services of the outgoing spokesperson and said that in recognition of her services, the Government of Pakistan had posted her as Pakistanas Ambassador to France. Mumtaz Zahra was appointed to the slot in November 2022, replacing Asim Iftikhar Ahmed who was also given the ambassadorial job in Paris. Now she will again replace him as Asim Iftikhar has moved to the United Nations as the Additional Permanent Representative. Currently, serving as Additional Secretary for Europe in the Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Shafqat Ali Khan has served as Pakistanas ambassador to Russia and Poland, DG Europe at MoFA and Deputy Permanent Representative to the United Nations in Geneva.",
    "summary": "Shafqat Ali Khan has been appointed as the new Foreign Office spokesperson, replacing Mumtaz Zahra Baloch. The outgoing spokesperson, Mumtaz Zahra, has been appointed as Pakistan's Ambassador to France.  Shafqat Ali Khan has previously served as ambassador to Russia and Poland.",
    "keywords": [
      "Shafqat Ali Khan",
      "Mumtaz Zahra Baloch",
      "Foreign Office",
      "spokesperson",
      "Pakistan",
      "France",
      "Ambassador"
    ]
  },
  "entities": [
    {
      "text": "Shafqat Ali Khan",
      "label": "PERSON",
      "wikidata_id": "null"
    },
    {
      "text": "Mumtaz Zahra Baloch",
      "label": "PERSON",
      "wikidata_id": "null"
    },
    {
      "text": "Foreign Office",
      "label": "ORGANIZATION",
      "wikidata_id": "Q307223"
    },
    {
      "text": "Ishaq Dar",
      "label": "PERSON",
      "wikidata_id": "null"
    },
    {
      "text": "Government of Pakistan",
      "label": "ORGANIZATION",
      "wikidata_id": "Q7368"
    },
    {
      "text": "Pakistan",
      "label": "LOCATION",
      "wikidata_id": "Q1042"
    },
    {
      "text": "Ambassador",
      "label": "PERSON",
      "wikidata_id": "Q190956"
    },
    {
      "text": "France",
      "label": "LOCATION",
      "wikidata_id": "Q142"
    },
    {
      "text": "Asim Iftikhar Ahmed",
      "label": "PERSON",
      "wikidata_id": "null"
    },
    {
      "text": "United Nations",
      "label": "ORGANIZATION",
      "wikidata_id": "Q1065"
    },
    {
      "text": "Geneva",
      "label": "LOCATION",
      "wikidata_id": "Q70"
    },
    {
      "text": "Russia",
      "label": "LOCATION",
      "wikidata_id": "Q159"
    },
    {
      "text": "Poland",
      "label": "LOCATION",
      "wikidata_id": "Q36"
    }
  ]
}