{
  "article_id": "2025-01-02_54d632300b36708dcc1f43344f644f7c",
  "source_info": {
    "source_name": "APP",
    "source_link": "https://www.app.com.pk/national/efforts-underway-to-make-nuclear-pakistan-an-economic-power-dar/",
    "retrieved_at": "2025-08-27T11:15:54.010Z"
  },
  "metadata": {
    "title": "Efforts underway to make nuclear Pakistan an economic power: Dar",
    "author": null,
    "date_published": "2025-01-02T09:31:00.000Z",
    "image_url": null,
    "categories": [],
    "word_count": 717,
    "reading_time_minutes": 4
  },
  "content": {
    "article_body": "ISLAMABAD, Jan 02 (APP): Deputy Prime Minister and Foreign Minister Ishaq Dar on Thursday said that the government was making all-out efforts to accomplish Pakistanas journey from nuclear to economic power and regain its lost stature in the world. The deputy prime minister, addressing a news conference, gave a roundup of the governmentas efforts to bring economic stability and enhance Pakistanas diplomatic footprints through bilateral and multilateral engagements with the latest one being the beginning of countryas two-year term as non-permanent member of the United Nations Securit Council for years 2025-26. Highlighting the high-level exchanges, and Pakistanas participation in and hosting of international events, he said the incumbent government had strived to enhance Pakistanas diplomatic footprint during its first 10 months, which led to the burying of the impression of an aisolated Pakistan.a The deputy prime minister said that the PML-N-led coalition government inherited huge challenges of around 25% policy rate, slow GDP growth and skyrocketing inflation. However, the governmentas prudent economic policies downed the policy rate to 13%, inflation below 5%, and remittance, foreign exchange reserves and exports on the rise. Ishaq Dar told the media that following Prime Minister Shehbaz Sharifas visits and effective engagements with the leadership of the UAE, Saudi Arabia, Kuwait and Azerbaijan, there were indications of around $29 billion investment in coming to Pakistan. He highlighted Pakistanas participation in the Nuclear Energy Summit, World Economic Forum in Saudi Arabia, OIC summit in Gambia, the visit of Saudi foreign minister, Iranas president late Ebrahim Raisi and his foreign minister, and that during all interactions Pakistan effectively raised the issue of Kashmir and ongoing Israelas genocide of Palestinian population. Pakistanas consistent efforts at the OIC summit in Gambia led to the appointment of OIC envoy on Islamophobia. He said Pakistan was among the very few countries that strongly advocated the implementation of UN resolutions on Palestine and ICJ ruling on the issue, besides condemning Israelas barbarism against innocent people. He said that besides hosting Palestinian medical students, Pakistan also dispatched relief aid to Gaza, Syria and Lebanon. The deputy prime ministeras presser also encompassed Pakistanas participation in D-8 summit and appointment of Ambassador Sohail Ahmed as its secretary general, PM Shehbazas visit to China and Kazakhstan, participation in UN General Assembly session, where he highlighted Kashmir and Gaza issues besides interacting with dozens of world leaders. Regarding his multiple interactions with UK Foreign Secretary David Lammy, he said a UK monitoring team was about to visit Pakistan in January which may follow the resumption of PIA flights to the UK, as the EU had already lifted the ban on the national flag carrier. He said Pakistanas hosting of SCO summit was awell-received and well-praiseda and informed the media that the World Muslim League would soon hold an event on the girls education at Jinnah Convention Center to be attended by 50 delegates from OIC states including 30 ministers. The deputy prime minister also mentioned his upcoming visit to Malaysia and Bangladesh in February. He said as Pakistan had started its two-year term as a non-permanent UNSC member, the country would make efforts to enhance diplomatic outreach and work for dispute resolution and upholding the UN charter. Responding to a question, Ishaq Dar told the media that Pakistan had eliminated terrorism in 2018 but it resurfaced due to the previous governmentas policy of opening the Afghan border and releasing the hardcore criminals. We want good trade ties with Afghanistan as it will pave the way to connectivity with other neighborly states like Uzbekistan. Regarding trade ties with India, he said aIt takes two to tangoa calling upon India to create an environment to help improve the relations. Later, responding to a question about a Washington Post story on Indian involvement in killing foreign nationals, Foreign Office spokesperson Mumtaz Zahra Baloch said Pakistan had already expressed concerns about the Indian involvement in extraterritorial killings, not only in Pakistan but also in other countries. She said Pakistan desired good ties with Afghanistan but at the same time, Pakistanas people and the security forces were capable enough to thwart any internal and external threat. To another query, she clarified that Pakistanas ports including Gwadar Port were purely meant for trade and development and the country had no design to offer any military bases to any foreign government.",
    "summary": "Deputy Prime Minister Ishaq Dar discussed Pakistan's efforts to transition from a nuclear to an economic power, highlighting diplomatic engagements and economic policies. He mentioned investments from various countries and Pakistan's stance on international issues like Kashmir and Palestine. The article also covered Pakistan's role in international forums and its efforts to improve relations with neighboring countries.",
    "keywords": [
      "Pakistan",
      "Ishaq Dar",
      "diplomacy",
      "economy",
      "foreign relations"
    ]
  },
  "entities": [
    {
      "text": "Ishaq Dar",
      "label": "PERSON",
      "wikidata_id": "null"
    },
    {
      "text": "Pakistan",
      "label": "LOCATION",
      "wikidata_id": "Q1045"
    },
    {
      "text": "UAE",
      "label": "LOCATION",
      "wikidata_id": "Q878"
    },
    {
      "text": "Saudi Arabia",
      "label": "LOCATION",
      "wikidata_id": "Q851"
    },
    {
      "text": "Kuwait",
      "label": "LOCATION",
      "wikidata_id": "Q817"
    },
    {
      "text": "Azerbaijan",
      "label": "LOCATION",
      "wikidata_id": "Q232"
    },
    {
      "text": "Nuclear Energy Summit",
      "label": "ORGANIZATION",
      "wikidata_id": "null"
    },
    {
      "text": "World Economic Forum",
      "label": "ORGANIZATION",
      "wikidata_id": "Q7279"
    },
    {
      "text": "OIC",
      "label": "ORGANIZATION",
      "wikidata_id": "Q12051"
    },
    {
      "text": "Gambia",
      "label": "LOCATION",
      "wikidata_id": "Q1004"
    },
    {
      "text": "Ebrahim Raisi",
      "label": "PERSON",
      "wikidata_id": "Q1057417"
    },
    {
      "text": "Kashmir",
      "label": "LOCATION",
      "wikidata_id": "Q689"
    },
    {
      "text": "Israel",
      "label": "LOCATION",
      "wikidata_id": "Q801"
    },
    {
      "text": "Palestine",
      "label": "LOCATION",
      "wikidata_id": "Q801"
    },
    {
      "text": "UN",
      "label": "ORGANIZATION",
      "wikidata_id": "Q1065"
    },
    {
      "text": "D-8",
      "label": "ORGANIZATION",
      "wikidata_id": "Q1150655"
    },
    {
      "text": "Sohail Ahmed",
      "label": "PERSON",
      "wikidata_id": "null"
    },
    {
      "text": "China",
      "label": "LOCATION",
      "wikidata_id": "Q148"
    },
    {
      "text": "Kazakhstan",
      "label": "LOCATION",
      "wikidata_id": "Q232"
    },
    {
      "text": "UN General Assembly",
      "label": "ORGANIZATION",
      "wikidata_id": "Q193699"
    },
    {
      "text": "David Lammy",
      "label": "PERSON",
      "wikidata_id": "Q523992"
    },
    {
      "text": "UK",
      "label": "LOCATION",
      "wikidata_id": "Q145"
    },
    {
      "text": "EU",
      "label": "ORGANIZATION",
      "wikidata_id": "Q458"
    },
    {
      "text": "SCO",
      "label": "ORGANIZATION",
      "wikidata_id": "Q188989"
    },
    {
      "text": "World Muslim League",
      "label": "ORGANIZATION",
      "wikidata_id": "Q8034878"
    },
    {
      "text": "Jinnah Convention Center",
      "label": "LOCATION",
      "wikidata_id": "null"
    },
    {
      "text": "Malaysia",
      "label": "LOCATION",
      "wikidata_id": "Q833"
    },
    {
      "text": "Bangladesh",
      "label": "LOCATION",
      "wikidata_id": "Q902"
    },
    {
      "text": "Afghanistan",
      "label": "LOCATION",
      "wikidata_id": "Q889"
    },
    {
      "text": "Uzbekistan",
      "label": "LOCATION",
      "wikidata_id": "Q265"
    },
    {
      "text": "India",
      "label": "LOCATION",
      "wikidata_id": "Q668"
    },
    {
      "text": "Washington Post",
      "label": "ORGANIZATION",
      "wikidata_id": "Q16602"
    },
    {
      "text": "Mumtaz Zahra Baloch",
      "label": "PERSON",
      "wikidata_id": "null"
    },
    {
      "text": "Gwadar Port",
      "label": "LOCATION",
      "wikidata_id": "Q311910"
    }
  ]
}