{
  "article_id": "2025-01-01_ae4695da7cddb79c084b6a207377f810",
  "source_info": {
    "source_name": "APP",
    "source_link": "https://www.app.com.pk/national/cabinet-terms-beginning-of-pakistans-term-as-unsc-member-big-achievement-on-diplomatic-front/",
    "retrieved_at": "2025-08-27T11:14:58.051Z"
  },
  "metadata": {
    "title": "Cabinet terms beginning of Pakistan’s term as UNSC member, big achievement on diplomatic front",
    "author": null,
    "date_published": "2025-01-01T12:41:00.000Z",
    "image_url": null,
    "categories": [],
    "word_count": 359,
    "reading_time_minutes": 2
  },
  "content": {
    "article_body": "ISLAMABAD, Jan 01 (APP): A meeting of the federal cabinet chaired by Prime Minister Muhammad Shehbaz Sharif on Wednesday termed Pakistanas two-year term as a non-permanent member of the United Nations Security Council (UNSC) as a significant achievement on the diplomatic front. Deputy Prime Minister and Foreign Minister Mohammad Ishaq Dar earlier, briefed the cabinet about Pakistanas term at the UNSC which began today. The meeting was held at the Prime Ministeras House, PM Office Media Wing said in a press release. During the meeting, the prime minister directed that the details of public sector imports from Gwadar Port, over the past three months, should be presented in the next meeting of the cabinet. The cabinet gave its principled approval for legislation on amendments to Section 3(7) of the Pakistan Telecommunication (Reorganization) Act, on the recommendation of the cabinet division/secretariat. It also recommended approval of the regulations for the appointment of Information Group officers as Press Officers at Pakistanas diplomatic missions abroad, proposed by the Ministry of Information and Broadcasting. These regulations would ensure a more transparent and merit-based process for the appointment of Information Group officers at Pakistanas foreign missions. The cabinet approved the registration/recognition of Liaquat University of Medical and Health Sciences, Thatta, on the recommendation of the Ministry of National Health. The cabinet, in light of the judgment in Human Rights Case No. 623-P/2017 by the honourable Supreme Court of Pakistan and the recommendation of the Ministry of National Health, approved the reconstitution of a committee to determine the prices of life-saving medical equipment. On the recommendation of the Ministry of National Food Security and Research, the cabinet approved sending the National Food Safety, Animal and Plant Health Authority Bill to Parliament. It also ratified the decisions taken in the meeting of the Cabinet Committee on Legislative Cases held on December 17, 2024. However, the ratification of amendments to the Citizenship Act has been deferred. The cabinet accorded its approval to the decisions taken in the meeting of the Economic Coordination Committee held on December 18. The cabinet ratified the decisions made in the meeting of the Cabinet Committee on State-Owned Enterprises held on December 24.",
    "summary": "The federal cabinet, led by Prime Minister Muhammad Shehbaz Sharif, convened and acknowledged Pakistan's two-year term as a non-permanent member of the United Nations Security Council (UNSC) as a diplomatic success. The cabinet addressed several matters, including public sector imports from Gwadar Port, amendments to the Pakistan Telecommunication (Reorganization) Act, and the appointment of Information Group officers to diplomatic missions.",
    "keywords": [
      "cabinet",
      "UNSC",
      "Pakistan",
      "diplomacy",
      "legislation",
      "appointments",
      "meetings"
    ]
  },
  "entities": [
    {
      "text": "Muhammad Shehbaz Sharif",
      "label": "PERSON",
      "wikidata_id": "Q106822837"
    },
    {
      "text": "UNSC",
      "label": "ORGANIZATION",
      "wikidata_id": "Q3753"
    },
    {
      "text": "Pakistan",
      "label": "LOCATION",
      "wikidata_id": "Q843"
    },
    {
      "text": "Mohammad Ishaq Dar",
      "label": "PERSON",
      "wikidata_id": "Q6896932"
    },
    {
      "text": "Prime Ministeras House",
      "label": "ORGANIZATION",
      "wikidata_id": "null"
    },
    {
      "text": "Gwadar Port",
      "label": "LOCATION",
      "wikidata_id": "Q3119598"
    },
    {
      "text": "Pakistan Telecommunication (Reorganization) Act",
      "label": "ORGANIZATION",
      "wikidata_id": "null"
    },
    {
      "text": "Ministry of Information and Broadcasting",
      "label": "ORGANIZATION",
      "wikidata_id": "Q6873534"
    },
    {
      "text": "Liaquat University of Medical and Health Sciences, Thatta",
      "label": "ORGANIZATION",
      "wikidata_id": "Q6541999"
    },
    {
      "text": "Ministry of National Health",
      "label": "ORGANIZATION",
      "wikidata_id": "null"
    },
    {
      "text": "Supreme Court of Pakistan",
      "label": "ORGANIZATION",
      "wikidata_id": "Q7620788"
    },
    {
      "text": "Ministry of National Food Security and Research",
      "label": "ORGANIZATION",
      "wikidata_id": "null"
    },
    {
      "text": "Parliament",
      "label": "ORGANIZATION",
      "wikidata_id": "Q11211"
    },
    {
      "text": "Economic Coordination Committee",
      "label": "ORGANIZATION",
      "wikidata_id": "null"
    },
    {
      "text": "Cabinet Committee on State-Owned Enterprises",
      "label": "ORGANIZATION",
      "wikidata_id": "null"
    }
  ]
}