{
  "article_id": "2025-01-09_d98079fdd5836aaf19fff21ed575d9c6",
  "source_info": {
    "source_name": "APP",
    "source_link": "https://www.app.com.pk/national/irsa-releases-33600-cusecs-water/",
    "retrieved_at": "2025-08-27T11:29:59.749Z"
  },
  "metadata": {
    "title": "IRSA releases 33,600 cusecs water",
    "author": null,
    "date_published": "2025-01-09T13:48:00.000Z",
    "image_url": null,
    "categories": [],
    "word_count": 151,
    "reading_time_minutes": 1
  },
  "content": {
    "article_body": "ISLAMABAD, Jan 09 (APP):Indus River System Authority (IRSA) on Thursday released 33,600 cusecs water from various rim stations with inflow of 40,800 cusecs. According to the data released by IRSA, water level in River Indus at Tarbela Dam was 1475.66 feet and was 77.66 feet higher than its dead level of 1,398 feet. Water inflow and outflow in the dam was recorded as 16,400 cusecs and 10,000 cusecs respectively. The water level in River Jhelum at Mangla Dam was 1133.35 feet, which was 83.35 feet higher than its dead level of 1,050 feet. The inflow and outflow of water was recorded 4,800 cusecs and 4,000 cusecs respectively. The release of water at Kalabagh, Taunsa , Guddu and Sukkur was recorded as 19,700, 12,500,A 5,000 and 6,000 cusecs respectively. Similarly, from River Kabul, a total of 14,300 cusecs of water released at Nowshera and 5,300 cusecs released from River Chenab at Marala.",
    "summary": "The Indus River System Authority (IRSA) released 33,600 cusecs of water from various rim stations in Pakistan on January 9. The release was part of the authority's efforts to manage water flow and prevent flooding in the country.",
    "keywords": [
      "water",
      "IRSA",
      "Pakistan",
      "dams",
      "rivers",
      "flood control"
    ]
  },
  "entities": [
    {
      "name": "Indus River System Authority",
      "type": "ORGANIZATION",
      "wikiDataId": null,
      "sentiment": "Neutral"
    },
    {
      "name": "IRSA",
      "type": "ORGANIZATION",
      "wikiDataId": "Q11914392",
      "sentiment": "Neutral"
    },
    {
      "name": "Tarbela Dam",
      "type": "LOCATION",
      "wikiDataId": null,
      "sentiment": "Neutral"
    },
    {
      "name": "River Indus",
      "type": "LOCATION",
      "wikiDataId": null,
      "sentiment": "Neutral"
    },
    {
      "name": "Pakistan",
      "type": "LOCATION",
      "wikiDataId": "Q33",
      "sentiment": "Neutral"
    },
    {
      "name": "Jan 09",
      "type": "DATE",
      "wikiDataId": null,
      "sentiment": "Neutral"
    },
    {
      "name": "Mangla Dam",
      "type": "LOCATION",
      "wikiDataId": null,
      "sentiment": "Neutral"
    },
    {
      "name": "River Jhelum",
      "type": "LOCATION",
      "wikiDataId": null,
      "sentiment": "Neutral"
    },
    {
      "name": "Kalabagh",
      "type": "LOCATION",
      "wikiDataId": null,
      "sentiment": "Neutral"
    },
    {
      "name": "Taunsa",
      "type": "LOCATION",
      "wikiDataId": null,
      "sentiment": "Neutral"
    },
    {
      "name": "Guddu",
      "type": "LOCATION",
      "wikiDataId": null,
      "sentiment": "Neutral"
    },
    {
      "name": "Sukkur",
      "type": "LOCATION",
      "wikiDataId": null,
      "sentiment": "Neutral"
    },
    {
      "name": "River Kabul",
      "type": "LOCATION",
      "wikiDataId": null,
      "sentiment": "Neutral"
    },
    {
      "name": "Nowshera",
      "type": "LOCATION",
      "wikiDataId": null,
      "sentiment": "Neutral"
    },
    {
      "name": "River Chenab",
      "type": "LOCATION",
      "wikiDataId": null,
      "sentiment": "Neutral"
    },
    {
      "name": "Marala",
      "type": "LOCATION",
      "wikiDataId": null,
      "sentiment": "Neutral"
    }
  ]
}